A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Associate Director and Vice President, Office Files of William McPeak FA704
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program Area V: Individual Behavior and Human Relations, 1950-1957; 1954-1956; III
  - Juvenile Delinquency - A Study of Etiology as a Guide to Prevention and Treatment, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 251)
  - Mental Deficiency - Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 252)
  - Mental Deficiency - General, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 253)
  - Mental Deficiency - Staff Interviews, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 254)
  - Mental Health, 1954-1958 (Box 9, Folder 255)
  - Merrill-Palmer School, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 256)
  - Menninger Foundation, 1950-1956 (Box 9, Folder 257)
  - Michigan, University of, 1953-1957 (Box 9, Folder 258)
  - Minnesota, University of, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 259)
  - MIT Communications Project, 1953 October 23 (Box 9, Folder 260)
  - Program Overview and Policy, 1951-1957 (Box 9, Folder 261)
  - National Probation and Parole Association, 1954-1957 (Box 9, Folder 262)
  - University Surveys, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 263)
- Program Areas I, II, and III, 1953-1964; 1954-1956; IV
  Series IV consists of correspondence and inter-office memoranda. This series is divided into the following three subseries by program area:
  A. Program Area I: The Establishment of Peace
  B. Program Area II: The Strengthening of Democracy
  C. Program Area III: The Strengthening of the Economy
  Each subseries is organized alphabetically; within each folder the items are in reverse chronological order.
  - Program Area I: Establishment of Peace, 1953-1956; A
    - Division of Overseas Activities, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 264)
    - European Program, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 265)
    - Overseas Development Program, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Overseas Representation Meeting, 1956 October-December (Box 10, Folder 267)
  - Program Area II: Strengthening of Democracy, 1954-1957; B
    - Fund for the Republic, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - Program Area III: Strengthening of the Economy, 1953-1964; C
    - Advisory Group on Economics and Behavioral Sciences, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - Resources for the Future, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Smog Problem, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 273)